JOSE M DEL VALLE

Software Developer

Email: josemdelvalle@outlook.com

Phone: (321) 324-7388 Location: St. Cloud FL

Portfolio link: https://portfolio-65ea0.web.app/

SUMMARY

Skilled developer with experience in various languages, design patterns, and frameworks such as Java, MVC, Spring, Hibernate, jQuery, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript as well as working with MySQL Database. Collaborated with analysts, managers and other developers in order to turn project details into technical requirements and develop applications intended for technical as well as non-technical users, providing maintenance to existing applications, updates to code and debugging in order to provide optimum performance. Possess excellent documentation skills as well as an ability to communicate effectively with all personnel helping overall team organization in English and Spanish.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Frameworks/Web Service: JAVA (J2EE,EJB, Servlets, JSP, JavaBeans, JDBC, JSTL), REST, Spring, jQuery, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, HTML5, Java with Spring MVC, SOAP, Hibernate, Visual Basic,

Database Management: MySQL **Operating Systems**: Windows

XML, ReactJS, SQL, Maven

Control Version: Git

Tools: Eclipse, Postman, Visual Studio, Apache Tomcat, Visual Studio Code, Microsoft Office, Web Services

EXPERIENCE

N2 Services Inc.

July 2020 - present

Java Intern

- Used ReactJS to design and create a shoe store web page. Used Firebase to store all shoe images and information used for the site.
- Designed and customized a responsive image downloading website with Bootstrap 4.
- Used HowlerJS to make a piano demo website.
- Used the google maps API to give the locations of different beaches located in Puerto Rico.
- Created a color picking game with JavaScript.
- Programmed an application called "Customer Tracker" using JAVA/J2EE, Java MVC (Model Viewer Controller) and following Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) procedures.
- Implemented the first phase of Customer Tracker called "Data Layer" creating a Data Base using MySQL and performing Class of the Entity (Objects), DAO (Data Access Object), using JPA (Java Persistence API) and Hibernate with Annotations.
- Performed structured and object-oriented programming to design Marketing Web applications using Java.

AirMaster Windows and Doors

January 2019 - August 2019

Production Supervisor

Approved employee time for payroll.

- Evaluated and recommended employees for pay increases.
- Ensured that safety policies were observed and followed.
- Measured production daily and created strategies for maximum efficiency.
- Met production schedule on a weekly basis.

Capstone Intern

November 2017 - June 2018

• Balanced production line using cycle times, redistributing labor, reducing work in process, and producing 54 more units per shift.

PRIMEX / EI-Com

June 2018 - October 2018

Continuous Improvement Engineer

- Contracted temporarily to improve factory's production efficiency.
- Facilitated a team of supervisors to implement lean methodologies in order to improve manufacturing workflow.
- Gathered cycle times for manufacturing operations to ensure and measure daily efficiency.
- Changed production batch work-flow to one-piece-flow production of units.

Techno Inventors

November 2017 - June 2018

Instructor

Taught children basic C++ syntax.

EDUCATION

- Polytechnic University of Puerto Rico Bachelor's in Industrial Engineering
- Atlantic University College Bachelor's in Science of Art and Design of Video Games with Programming